Hi I’m ALANNA. I’m part of a small team of open-source developers, facilitators and activists here in New Zealand.
こんにちは、私はアラナと言います。 ここニュージーランドにある、オープンソース開発者やコンサルタント、活動家などで構成される小さなチームの一員です。
We’re working on a project called Loomio.
私たちはLoomioというプロジェクトに携わっています。
It’s a simple online tool for collaborative decision-making.
それは共同意志決定のためのシンプルなオンラインツールです。
Hi I’m RICHARD. when I got involved in the Occupy movement I experienced how massively empowering it can be when everyone’s voice is included in a decision-making process.
どうも、リチャードといいます。 意思決定プロセスで全員の声が含まれるととんでもなく大きなパワーを与えるということを、私はオキュパイ運動に参加した際に経験しました。
But if it can only happen in person, it can never work at a large scale.
しかし、それが自身にのみ起こったのでは、大規模にはなりえません。
It seems crazy, but there’s no easy way to make decisions together online.
おかしいと思えるかもしれませんが、オンラインで一緒に意思決定をするのに簡単な方法はないのです。
Email and social media just weren’t built for bringing online discussion to clear agreement.
メールやソーシャルメディアは、合意を明確にするためのオンラインディスカッションをもたらすために作られていないのです。
It’s like this missing piece of the Internet, that we need for turning online talk into real-world action.
オンライントークを現実世界のアクションに変えるために私たちが必要としているのが、インターネットのこの欠けているピースのようなものなのです。
So that’s what we’ve been working on for the past 18 months.
そして、それが私たちが過去18ヶ月間取り組んできたものです。
As soon as we released our prototype, we were swamped by thousands of groups around the world - from student movements and City Councils, to software projects and community groups.
試作品をリリースしてすぐに、学生運動や市議会から始まりソフトウェアプロジェクトや地域社会のグループに至るまで、私たちは世界中の何千といるグループに圧倒されました。
We’ve learned a lot from all the people doing great things with the prototype.
試作品を使って素晴らしいことをしていたすべての人たちから、多くのことを学びました。
We know its potential, and we know its limitations.
その可能性を私たちは知っています、そしてその限界を私たちは知っています。
Now it’s time to build the real thing.
今、本物を作る時がやってきました。
Loomio 1.0 - a tool for truly inclusive decision-making.
Loomio 1.0 ー 真に包括的な意思決定のためのツール
At its core, it’s actually really simple:
その核心は、実はすごくシンプルです：
you talk things through and hear different perspectives,
あなたは何かについて語り、異なった考えに耳を傾け、
build agreement and work through any concerns,
合意を形成し、どの懸念にも対応し、
and decide a clear course of action that works for everyone.
そしてすべての人に働く、はっきりとした行動の計画を決定します。
This flexible, dynamic process unlocks collective wisdom, coming to better outcomes together than any individual would have on their own.
この柔軟でダイナミックなプロセスが連携した知恵の鍵を開け、個人が思いつくどれよりも良い結論に一緒にたどり着くことができます。
Loomio 1.0 will work on all devices, opening it up to parts of the world where computers are scarce.
世界中のコンピューターが不足している場所にも開かれるように、Loomio 1.0 はすべてのデバイスで動きます。
You can host it yourself, to take complete control of your own privacy.
あなたの個人情報を完璧に制御するために、自分のインスタンスをインストールできます。
Most importantly, it’s designed to be super easy to use and accessible, so anyone can participate.
最も重要なこととして、誰でも参加できるように非常に使いやすくそしてアクセスしやすくデザインされています。
Loomio will always be free and open-source software.
Loomioは常に自由であり、オープンソースのソフトウェアです。
We're building public infrastructure for decision-making, held in the commons.
意思決定のための、共通して持たれる公的なインフラを私たちは築いているのです。
By resourcing Loomio through crowdfunding, the project can be driven by the community of people who want it to happen, not by advertisers, or people who want to sell your data.
クラウドファンディングを通してLoomioに資金を与えることで、広告主やあなたのデータを売りたい人たちによってではなく、それを起こしてほしい人たちのコミュニティによってプロジェクトは動かされます。
We’ve done all the research and design, and now we  just have to build it.
私たちはすべての調査とデザインを終え、今はただそれを作らなければいけないだけです。
An amazing crew has come together with exactly the right skills to make this happen: a development team that’s passionate about user-centred design, coupled with group process experts with decades of facilitation experience.
ユーザー中心の設計に熱意がある開発者や経験豊富なグループのコミュニケーションのコンサルタントなど、Loomioを作るために、必要な技能を持ってるチームが集まりました。。
To take this next step, the core team needs to dedicate all of their time to it without worrying about how they’re going to feed themselves.
次の段階を取るために、チームがフルタイムで働ければなりません。
And that’s why right now we need your help.
そして、それがまさに私たちがあなたの助けを求めている理由なのです。
We’re embracing the gift economy and asking for your support, so we can give something amazing back to the world.
私たちは人間の寛容さを信じているので、何か素晴らしいものを世界に返すことができるように、あなたのサポートをお願いします。
You’re not just supporting a vision, you’re getting a tool that will make a difference in your own life, in your work, and in your community.
あなたはただ幻想をサポートするのではなく、あなた自身の生活、仕事、コミュニティにおいて力を発揮するツールを手に入れるのです。
So it’s up to all of us.
したがって、それは私たち次第なのです
Will this missing piece of the internet be developed on open platforms, for the public good?
インターネットのこの欠けているピースは、公益のためにオープンプラットフォームで開発されるでしょうか？
You can help to make that decision right now, by giving to this project.
Loomioをサポートすることによってたった今、その決定を行う手助けができます。